<Chapter Label="Intro">
<Heading>Introduction</Heading>

<Section Label="IntroOverview">
  <Heading>Overview</Heading>
  This package provides methods for calculations with certain translation surfaces called origamis. An origami (also known as square-tiled surface) is a finite covering of a torus which is ramified at most over one point. It can be described in the following way from two permutations <M>\sigma_x, \sigma_y \in S_d</M>. We take <M>d</M> squares <M>Q_1, \dots, Q_d</M> and glue the lower side of <M>Q_i</M> to the upper side of <M>Q_{\sigma_y(i)}</M> and the right side of <M>Q_i</M> to the left side of <M>Q_{\sigma_x(i)}</M>. We require origamis to be connected and thus the group generated by <M>\sigma_x</M> and <M>\sigma_y</M>  acts transitively on <M>\{1,\ldots,d\}</M>. In this package we identify an origami with a pair of permutations, which acts transitively on <M>\{1, \dots, d\}</M> up to simultaneous conjugation. This corresponds to renumbering the squares. By choosing a certain numbering in a canonical way one can
  achieve a canonical representative.
  
  <Par/>
  
  We are especially interested in the so-called Veech group of an origami. This is a finite-index subgroup of <M>SL_2(\mathbb{Z})</M> which carries a lot of information about the geometric and dynamic properties of the underlying translation surface.
  For further information about origamis and translation surfaces in general see e.g. <Cite Key="phd_zmiaikou"/>, <Cite Key="phd_schmithuesen"/>, <Cite Key="teichmueller_discs_hubert_lelievre"/>, <Cite Key="inf_transl_surf_randecker"/> and <Cite Key="flat_surf_zorich"/>.
</Section>

<Section>
  <Heading>Notations</Heading>
    Since we are mainly interested in Veech groups of origamis, which are subgroups of <M>SL_2(\mathbb{Z})</M> of finite index, we fix two generators of <M>SL_2(\mathbb{Z})</M>
    
    <Display>
      S =
     \left( {\begin{array}{cc}
      0 &amp; -1 \\
      1 &amp; 0 \\
     \end{array} } \right)
   </Display>

    and

    <Display>
      T =
     \left( {\begin{array}{cc}
      1 &amp; 1 \\
      0 &amp; 1 \\
     \end{array} } \right).
   </Display>

    Furthermore we fix the free group <M>F</M> generated by <M>\tilde{S}</M> and <M>\tilde{T}</M>.
    We consider the canonical epimorphism <M>\pi: F\to SL_2(\mathbb{Z})</M> with <M>\pi(\tilde{S})=S</M> and <M>\pi(\tilde{T})=T</M>.
</Section>

</Chapter>
